<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Jerry Qin]]></title><description><![CDATA[Personal Website and Blog]]></description><link>https://jerryqin.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 07:59:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[We Don't Say Love]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blank verse poem and discussion on filial affection and piety in Chinese culture.]]></description><link>https://jerryqin.com/posts/we-don&apos;t-say-love</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jerryqin.com/posts/we-don&apos;t-say-love</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my first (real) blog post! Below is a piece in iambic pentameter blank verse I was working on a while back:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Chinese, we don’t say love.&lt;br&gt;
instead my mother asks, “&lt;ruby&gt;
你 &lt;rp&gt;(&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;rt&gt;nǐ&lt;/rt&gt;&lt;rp&gt;)&lt;/rp&gt;
吃 &lt;rp&gt;(&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;rt&gt;chī&lt;/rt&gt;&lt;rp&gt;)&lt;/rp&gt;
了 &lt;rp&gt;(&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;rt&gt;le&lt;/rt&gt;&lt;rp&gt;)&lt;/rp&gt;
吗 &lt;rp&gt;(&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;rt&gt;ma&lt;/rt&gt;&lt;rp&gt;)&lt;/rp&gt;
&lt;/ruby&gt;”                                 (“have you eaten”)&lt;br&gt;
repeatedly as if I never ate&lt;br&gt;
when I was far from home. She says it like&lt;br&gt;
I’d only miss the warmth of homemade soups&lt;br&gt;
and not the warmth of sitting next to her&lt;br&gt;
on weekend evenings as we watched TV.&lt;br&gt;
In Mandarin, we don’t admit our love.&lt;br&gt;
Instead my mother brought a plate of fruit&lt;br&gt;
up to my room in silence while I slept&lt;br&gt;
before departing home for work each day.&lt;br&gt;
We don’t say love. Instead we might say “&lt;ruby&gt;
疼 &lt;rp&gt;(&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;rt&gt;téng&lt;/rt&gt;&lt;rp&gt;)&lt;/rp&gt;
&lt;/ruby&gt;”                  (“to hurt/love fondly”)&lt;br&gt;
as if to note that love inherently&lt;br&gt;
implies self-sacrifice. We might say this,&lt;br&gt;
but never love. For love is too simple&lt;br&gt;
a word. Just two small letters in a row;&lt;br&gt;
a single syllable that manifests&lt;br&gt;
with barely any effort from within.&lt;br&gt;
And love is way too large a word to be&lt;br&gt;
encompassed utterly in a small one.&lt;br&gt;
So in my family, we don’t say love.&lt;br&gt;
Instead, as I depart my room each day&lt;br&gt;
I call my mom to ask, “你吃了吗?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally wrote this poem for a class I took to develop my poetry-writing and practice writing in form. Some technical details about this poem: it’s written in iambic pentameter blank verse. I chose this topic to address how love is expressed and perceived in Asian communities. Specifically, I wanted to address the phenomenon that Asian-American families rarely say that they love each other and, more often than not, choose to express themselves through selfless action instead of words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I often struggled to reconcile the two, often opposing sides of my identity. Chinese and American culture disagree fundamentally on issues regarding an individual’s identity and purpose. While one favors creative expression and individualism, the other prioritizes one’s connection and duty to family. Growing up in America andbein immersed in American media and education has helped me develop an understanding of my nation and myself. It’s part the experience that drove many of our parents to immigrate to the U.S. in the first place one that has provided many of us with opportunities and freedoms that were unavailable to our parents. Yet this same experience has the power to unequivocally estrange us from our Asian culture and heritage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while I’ve come to better understand my identity as a Chinese-American, I sometimes still have trouble internalizing some of the nuances of Chinese culture. This poem is my personal attempt to comment on and appreciate the nuance of love in Chinese culture. While we don’t express it directly through our words, we demonstrate the immensity of our love for one another through the subtle actions and comments that often go unnoticed by each other. As a result, expressing love and appreciation for others has become synonymous with “show don’t tell” in my daily life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to briefly discuss the role of using Chinese phrases and words in this poem as well. Just as words cannot express the depth of the love we feel for our family and friends, I didn’t feel that English was sufficient to communicate just how loudly our actions speak for us. Instead, Chinese characters and phrases, especially ones commonly used to convey love and affection, were better suited for this role. The phrases I chose to use &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be translated into English, yet (as Chinese speakers would agree) the connotation of these words are woefully lost in translation. These words in their original form were so much more accurate to my experience than anything I could come up with in English, and I hope they help underscore the uniqueness of the Asian-American experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for tuning in! I’m currently working on setting up a subscription form directly on my website, but please fill out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/xvFZcg22b1UGURso9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;form&lt;/a&gt; if you would like me to add you to the mailing list for the future!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to My Website!]]></title><description><![CDATA[A quick introduction to my blog!]]></description><link>https://jerryqin.com/posts/welcome-to-my-website</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jerryqin.com/posts/welcome-to-my-website</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;!-- - [Moving Forward](#moving-forward) --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings! This is the first of hopefully many posts that I’ll be uploading onto this platform. This website has been a goal of mine for a while now and the quarantine has given me an opportunity (in my boredom) to finally get on top of it. I’ve been challenging myself recently to write more in an attempt to document my thoughts and become a more mindful person in the process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to be posting every couple of weeks or so on a variety of topics but primarily on mathematics, poetry, and stand-up, along with general ideas and discussions I find interesting. This will include updates on my research, drafts of poems I’ve been working on, and commentary on current events and pop culture. Hopefully this blog will become a collection of such content that can provide some insight on some of these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;moving-forward&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#moving-forward&quot; aria-label=&quot;moving forward permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Moving Forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be posting semi-regularly and adding functionality to this website as I become more comfortable with web development. I’m currently working on setting up a subscription for people who are interested in keeping up with this blog and other details as I decide on where I want to to take this (If you’re interested in subscribing, head over to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/xvFZcg22b1UGURso9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;form&lt;/a&gt; and I will add you to the mailing list after I have it set up). If you’re interested in learning more about me, please feel free to navigate around this site or email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto: jerry.qin@vanderbilt.edu&quot;&gt;jerry.qin@vanderbilt.edu&lt;/a&gt;. In the meantime, thanks for tuning in and I hope you’ll find some of the content illuminating and thought-provoking.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>